Now what you've done so far is pretty good.
We can use variables now to change the MAC address to any mac address we want easily and to any interface.
But every time the user wants to change these variables they have to open the code they have to open
the program and modify its code manually which is not very good.
It'll be nicer if we can get the user to input the variables that they want through the terminal.
So there are a number of ways to do that.
And in this lecture we're going to talk about the import function.
So we have to do is just use the input function like so put a string that will be displayed to the user.
So for example ask for your age and then initialize that to be stored in a variable called anything
we want.
And in this example we're calling it age then the user is going to see this.
What's your age.
If they import for example 10 then 10 will be stored in this variable.
And then we can print it again.
This is very boring.
So what we're going to do is we're going to use something within our cool code and ask the user to enter
the interface and then you mark and then use it in here.
So we already have a variable called interface and all we have to do instead of initializing it like
this.
We want the user to put this value for us.
So instead of initializing it and saying it you are here we're going to say the interface is going to
equal to the input that the user will give me.
And inside this we're going to put the text that the user will see.
So we're going to ask for the interface.
Same goes for the Mac.
So instead of initializing the Mac within the code like this we're going to say Neumark is going to
equal two.
And I want that to be taken from the user input so using the input function.
And I want the user to see a message asking for the Neumark.
So in that message I'm going to say new Mac and that's it.
We're going to start this and let's run it and see what it's going to look like.
So Python might change your not.
Why.
And as you can see the program will not execute further code.
It will stop and it will first ask me for the interface.
So whenever I put Lan's zero in here this will automatically initialize interface to line 0 because
you said interface equals input and I'm given the input in here so the user is given the input themselves
through the terminal.
Now if I enter now we get an error because this is actually a Python 3 function.
So we have to say Python 3 in here because if you just type python it'll run with Python 2.7.
So we run this again as asking me for the interface.
We set down to zero.
Now the code will stop again and it asks me for the Neumark.
So we're going to set that 0 0 1 1 2 2 3 3 4 4 and I'm going to go for 4:4 again to just use something
different to make sure that this code is going to work.
And now it's already the code has already initialized interface with LAN 0.
Once I hit Enter it's going to initialize Neumark with the value that I just inputted which is the Neumark
then is going to use it in here and in here exactly the same way as before.
So let's set enter and see what happens.
It's print in the right print statement for also sell on us that it's change your MAC address for line
zero to this MAC address.
So again the print statement.
It's a really good way of knowing that interface and Neumark actually hold the values that we want so
they hold the values that the user did actually input.
Because when your code gets more complicated you can make mistakes and maybe the variables will not
hold the value that you expect them to hold.
So let's do it config line zero and see if the map changed.
And as you can see it actually did get changed to the MAC address that we want.
Now going back to this error we got this because we were running the code used in Python 2.7 not Python
3.
Like I said these two versions are very very similar.
So if you want this code to run with Python 2.7 all you have to do is just type pro input instead of
input.
So it's just the function has a different name.
So we change that to raw input and we change that to raw input
going down.
And we're just going to run at this time with Python not Python 3 had Antar asked me for the interface.
Let's set it to Etihad zero this time and said the new Mach 2 0 0 1 1 2 2 3 3 4 4 2 2 enter.
We get the right values in the print statement the right interface and the right MAC address.
And if we do ifconfig 88 0 you can see the MAC address changed to 4:4 2 to the same MAC address that
we said in here.
So this just goes to show you that Python 2.7 and 3 are very similar.
Once you know one of them you can use the other.
So that's it for this lecture.
I just wanted to introduce the input or the raw input function that allows the user to initialize variables
or interact with the program through the terminal.
So when they actually run the program instead of having to manually modify the code every time they
need to change a variable.